BIANCA CARDONA RIVERA

During my 3 years of professional experience as a Front-End Developer, I have had expertise in crafting websites and desktop applications. using a versatile stack including, ES6, HTML5, ReactJS, NodeJS, JSON & RESTful APIs, MongoDB, etc.

My journey in software development has not only seen improvement in my technical prowess but also significant growth in my soft skills, making me an effective communicator, problem solver, and adaptable professional in addition to my technical capabilities.

CONTACT DETAILS

333 844 6612 ZAPOPAN, JALISCO biancardona.rivera@gmail.com

ENGLISH LEVEL B2



/Biancardona



/in/biancardona/



/bianca.web.app/



/fitterhappiergdl

EXPERIENCE

CURRENTLY

I'm actively engaged in developing a serverless project with AWS, Typescript, CDK V2, CloudFormation, Lambda and Amplify.

FULL STACK DEVELOPER Improving (Apr 2023- Dic 2023)

Throughout this period, I've dedicated myself to mastering my front end stack and enhancing my backend by developing various types of applications using technologies such as NodeJS, MongoDB, React, Tailwind CSS, applying coding best practices.

TECHNOLOGY STACK: JavaScript, (ES6), React, NodeJS, MongoDB, Tailwind, Css, mySQL.

FORM CREATOR Improving/Auxita (Mar 2021-Apr 2023)

I was able to work directly with the client, developing and rigorously testing a digital adaptation of PDF forms. We employed a library called Blockly, specifically designed for constructing visual programming editors. This solution was aimed at enabling end-users,

primarily physicians, to seamlessly input information into these forms through an application.

ACHIEVEMENTS: The enhanced platforms facilitated seamless collaboration between patients and doctors, streamlined development processes, ensured data security, and provided scalability and reliability. The project's success serves as a testament to the value of strong partnerships and the effective implementation of technology-driven solutions.

INTERN FRONTEND DEVELOPER Improving (2020-2021)

Learned about agile methodologies applied in a real project with a large development team. Worked with Scrum and Kanban, and the usage of Jira to facilitate the tracking of activities, creation of internal checklists in order to promote the efficiency of the development process. Created and organized Confluence documentation, created and helped coordinate team activities to promote a healthier and more integrated work environment.

EDUCATION

2019-2020. LABORATORIA.

I was trained on JS Frontend development by creating several projects implementing agile methodologies, using Javascript, HTML5, CSS, React, among others. Including technical and soft skills as well as self-study techniques.

2014-2016.SPORT NUTRITIONIST

Sport Nutrition from SportMed Clinic + ISAK Level 1 Anthropometry.

HERE ARE SOME OF MY PERSONAL PROJECTS

Veterinary Patients App

Tailored for veterinarians, this application provides platform to effortlessly manage and organize patient data. The system boasts secure login and authentication features, seamlessly interfacing with a database to execute all CRUD methods for efficient and handling of patient information. TECHNOLOGY STACK: JavaScript, (ES6), React, Context Hook, Express, NodeJS, MongoDB, Tailwind, Vite. (Click to visit the WebSite).

LoanQuote-REACT

A financial application that calculates the repayment amount based on the borrowing term and loan amount. TECHNOLOGY STACK: JavaScript(ES6), React, React-Router-Dom, Tailwind. Vite. GitHub.

(Click to visit the WebSite).

Rick & Morty Data

Web page to display, filter and search a set of data of all the characters in Rick & Morty series.

TECHNOLOGY STACK: HTML5, CSS3, Vanilla JavaScript(ES6), Git.

(Click to visit the WebSite)

TravelAgency-NODE

A dynamic web application seamlessly linked to a database, designed to present information for a travel agency. TECHNOLOGY STACK: NodeJs, Express, mySQL, Sequelize, Boostrap, Pug, GitHub, MVC Architecture, Filess, TablePlus.

(Click to visit the WebSite).

Weather APP

Within this application, an API is invoked to dynamically retrieve and display current weather information based on user-inputted city and country details

TECHNOLOGY STACK: HTML5, CSS3, Vanilla JavaScript(ES6), Github, Netlify, Parcel.

(Click to visit the WebSite).

Movie & Lab

Website created with create-react-app where users could find out information about many kind of movies handling the OMDB & IMDB APIs

TECHNOLOGY STACK: ES6, ReactJS/Hooks, Git, Bootstrap. (Click to visit the WebSite)